I won't work overtime today
本宫今天不加班
Episode 10
第十集
Mr. Wei
魏总
The vice president of our company
我们公司的副总
Wei Yahan
魏雅涵
She was in charge of
她之前是负责
Internal operations of the company
公司内部运营的
She's in charge this year
今年她去负责
Overseas branches managed
海外分公司管理了
Why did she come back suddenly
她怎么突然回来了
Sister Jiaojiao
皎皎姐
You know her, too
你也认识她啊
Sort of knowing each other
算是认识吧
Have I met Concubine Wei
见过魏贵妃
Quick free gift
快快免礼
Since the day you became a concubine
自你封嫔那日后
A matter that has been complicated
一直被繁杂的事务
Delayed
耽搁了
I'm only free to be with you today
今天才有空和你
Have a good chat
好好聊聊天
After that day
那日过后
Quiet Concubine
静嫔
Zhao Bin and the others didn't
赵嫔她们没有
Let's embarrass you again
再为难你吧
Thanks to Concubine Wei
多亏了魏贵妃
No more
再也没有了
There's no need to argue with them
犯不着和她们计较
Don't be so shouting
你不要叫得这么生分
From now on, we will be called sisters
以后我们就以姐妹相称
Good
好
This
这个
Think of it as a sister celebrating you
就当是姐姐庆祝你
A congratulatory gift from a concubine
封嫔的贺礼
Imperial Concubine
贵妃娘娘
This is a reward given to you by the emperor
这可是皇上赏赐给您的
Your favorite bead hairpin
您最喜欢的一根珠钗啊
Speak out of turn
多嘴
It's hard for me to hit it off with my sister
我与妹妹难得投缘
Isn't it just a bead hairpin
不就是一根珠钗嘛
Thank you, Concubine Wei
多谢魏贵妃
What else do you call me
你还叫我什么
Thank you sister
谢谢姐姐
You see
你看
Mingyue, you say
明月 你说
If time really could
要是时间真的能
Stop at this moment
停在这一刻
How nice would that be
那多好啊
When did you come back
什么时候回来的
The plane arrived just after it landed this morning
今早飞机刚落地就来了
Thanks for hard work
辛苦了
Our Mr. Li is so indifferent
我们李总这么冷漠呀
When I come back, you just say something
我回来你就一句
Thank you for your hard work. Send me
辛苦了打发我
Without a welcome hug
都没有个欢迎的拥抱
Your return is equivalent to going home
你回来就相当于回家
Don't need a welcome, right?
也不需要欢迎了吧
Mr. Wei came back so soon
魏总这么快就回来了
Why is it soon
怎么就快了
You don't know
你是不知道
General Wei at the beginning of the year
年初魏总领的
But for a year
可是一年的
Key Performance Indicators
关键绩效指标
This is completely
这可整整
A quarter ahead of schedule
提前了一个季度
So powerful
这么厉害
I've heard that
我早就听说
Mr. Wei is both talented and beautiful
魏总才貌双全
Unexpectedly
没想到
It was really like this when I saw it today
今日一见真的是这样
I don't know either
也不知道
Her baby kiss with Mr. Li
她跟李总的娃娃亲
Is it true or false
到底是真的还是假的
Everyone be quiet
大家安静一下
Ready for a meeting
准备开会了
Announce a few things
宣布几个事情
Recently the company just finished
最近公司刚刚完成了
A big round of hiring
一轮大型招聘
Group III of Personnel Department
人事部三组
In this event
在这次活动中
Performed very well
表现得非常出色
Worthy of recognition
值得肯定
Additionally
另外
Next Personnel Department
接下来人事部
The most important job is
最重要的工作就是
Training of new employees
新员工的培训
And within the company
以及公司内部
Transfer of post
岗位的调动
Mr. Wei just came back
魏总刚好已经回来了
In the future, the company's internal operations
以后公司内部运营
Or leave it to her
还是交给她负责
Mr. Li, can I say a few words
李总 我可以说两句吗
Of course
当然
Everyone here
在座的各位
There are a lot of new faces
有很多新面孔
But everyone should
不过大家应该
You know me
都认识我吧
Year of the year
年初
Mr. Li put overseas companies
李总把海外的公司
Entrust me
托付给我
It was originally planned for a year
本来计划是一年的时间
But I really miss everyone
但是我真的太想大家了
So the first time
所以第一时间
Just rush back to reunite with everyone
就赶回来和大家团聚
Please take care of me in the future
以后还请多多关照
Not bad, still very powerful
不错呀 依然很厉害
Of course
那当然
Ordinary people can advance one quarter
普通人能提前一个季度
Are the key performance indicators completed
完成关键绩效指标吗
I'm talking about her
我说的是她
These words are very powerful
这番话很厉害
On the one hand
一方面
Closer to colleagues
拉近了和同事
The distance between
之间的距离
On the other hand
另一方面
Showed again
又展示了
One's own ability to work
自己的工作能力
It can be said that it kills multiple birds with one stone
可谓是一举多得呀
But
不过
The intention of her remarks
她这番话的用意
What is it
是什么呢
But
不过
Overseas business is just getting started
海外的业务才刚刚起步
I'm not very relieved either
我也不是很放心
Want to see too
也想看看
Is there a suitable person
有没有合适的人
Can take over for me
能够替我接管
Now overseas companies
现在海外公司
It is the time for rapid development
正是迅速发展的时候
As long as you go, you will definitely have achievements
只要去肯定有业绩
This worked overseas for a few years
这在海外工作几年
I will definitely be promoted when I come back
回来铁定升职
It's a meeting. Don't talk
开会呢 不要说话了
Sister Jiaojiao
皎皎姐
If it were you, would you go
如果是你 你去吗
I'd like to go
我倒是想去啊
But with my current
不过以我现在的
Competence and seniority
能力和资历
It's simply impossible
根本不可能
And I am interested in western countries
而且我对西洋国家
Those languages
那些语言
Not knowing anything
一窍不通
Can't go at all
根本去不了
I just heard Mr. Li praise the third group of personnel
刚刚听李总夸人事三组
Excellent job performance
工作表现出色
I propose
我提议
Why don't you let the leaders of the three groups
不如让三组的组长
To take over overseas companies
去接管海外的公司
It's called He Jiaojiao, right
是叫何皎皎是吧
What do you think
你觉得呢
She is inexperienced
她经验不足
I'm afraid I'm not
恐怕难以胜任
I see
我看
Why don't you let promise go
不如让许诺去吧
He's been with me for so many years
他跟了我这么多年
It's time to be alone
是时候独当一面了
Not Mr. Li, I
不是 李总 我
He Jiaojiao, what do you think
何皎皎 你觉得呢
Mr. Li
李总
I very much agree with your opinion
我非常认可您的看法
But sometimes
可是 有的时候
Experience and competence
经验和能力
Not necessarily proportional
不一定成正比
Sometimes all that's missing is
有时候缺的只是
An opportunity
一个机会
What do you mean is
你的意思是
I didn't give you a chance
我没给你机会
Of course Jiaojiao doesn't mean that
皎皎当然不是这个意思
Our company
我们公司
Will give each
会给每一个
Excellent young opportunities
优秀的年轻人机会
It's just Mr. Li
只是 李总
Xu Tezhu is gone
许特助走了
What about your assistant
那您的助理
It's Mr. Li
是 李总
Let He Jiaojiao try it
让何皎皎试试吧
Didn't she say she didn't give her a chance
她不是说没给她机会吗
Mr. Wei, what do you think
魏总 你觉得呢
Mr. Li's decision
李总的决定
Of course I support it with both hands
我当然双手支持
Is He Jiaojiao competent
何皎皎 能胜任吗
Thank you Mr. Wei and Mr. Li for your trust
多谢魏总和李总的信任
But my experience is insufficient
可是我的经验不足
As an assistant
作为助理的话
Not very good at taking care of people either
也不是太会照顾人
And Special Assistant Xu
而且许特助
I've been with you for so many years
跟了您这么多年
That
那个
Do you want to hear my opinion
你们想听听我的意见吗
-Assistant Xu, do you have a problem -Assistant Xu, do you have a problem
-许特助 你有意见 -许特助 你有意见
No no
没有 没有
Dare not dare not dare not dare
不敢 不敢 不敢
He Jiaojiao
何皎皎
Think clearly and give me the answer
你想清楚了 再给我答案
Adjourned the meeting
散会
Jiaojiao
皎皎
What about this recruitment
这次招聘的事情
I heard Mr. Li say
我听李总说了
Well done
做得好
Thank you, Mr. Wei
谢谢魏总
What about the assistant
助理的事呢
You don't have to worry too much
你不用太担心
Mr. Li looks very serious
李总看起来很严肃
But he's actually a
但其实他是一个
Nice guy
挺好的人
But if you're really worried
不过你要实在担心的话
You can tell me whenever you want
你也可以随时和我说
Don't call me Mr. Wei in the future
以后也别叫我魏总了
Call me Sister Yahan
叫我雅涵姐吧
Thank you, Mr. Wei, for your concern
多谢魏总关心
Okay
行
If you have something to do there, go and do it first
你那儿有事你就先去忙
Good bye Mr. Wei
好 拜拜 魏总
Mr. Wei is so gentle
魏总好温柔啊
Does this look good
这个好看吗
Good-looking
好看
Imperial Concubine He
何妃娘娘
What's wrong
怎么了
But my sister has something to do with me
可是姐姐找我有事
Empress
娘娘
Imperial Concubine
贵妃娘娘
Please go to Asahi Palace
请您去朝日宫一叙
Good
好
Let's go, little pine nuts
走吧 小松子
I made it with my own hands
把我亲手做的
Bring Poria Cake
茯苓糕带上
Good
好
Give my sister a taste
给姐姐尝尝
Empress
娘娘
Would you like to dress up again
您要不再梳妆打扮一番
Our mother heard that
我们家娘娘听说
How many days have you been
您已经好几日
Haven't seen the emperor
没见过皇上了
She invited the emperor
她邀请皇上
Go to Asahi Palace together
一同前去朝日宫
My sister is so kind to me
姐姐待我可真是太好了
You go first
你先去吧
Great, little master
太好了 小主
How about it
怎么样
Your Majesty, the ink is finished
皇上 墨磨好了
Empress
娘娘
Pay greetings to the emperor
给皇上请安
Pay greetings to the imperial concubine
给贵妃娘娘请安
Sister, come quickly
妹妹 快来
Unexpectedly
没想到
You two have a close relationship
你们两个关系倒是亲密
Just in time, let's enjoy the painting together
正好 那就一同赏画吧
Appreciate paintings
赏画
My sister and I hit it off
我和妹妹一见如故
The emperor likes his sister
皇上喜欢妹妹
Naturally, I like her, too
我自然也喜欢她
Sister Mingyue
明月妹妹
Look at this picture
你看这幅画
Do you have any ideas
可有什么想法
The concubines are poor in talent and poor in learning
臣妾才疏学浅
Can't understand
看不懂
Don't be afraid
别害怕
Say whatever comes to mind
想到什么就说什么
The painting
这幅画
Pretty beautiful
挺漂亮的
What else
还有呢
And
还有
And it draws well
还有 还有它画得好
This is the previous dynasty
这是前朝
The most famous painter
最富盛名的画家
Tang Kefan's authentic work
唐可凡的真迹
To your mouth
到了你的嘴里
It seems a little tacky
倒是显得有些俗气了
Your Majesty, why should you be angry
皇上 您何必生气
Sister Mingyue
明月妹妹
I didn't read any books when I was a child
小时候没念过什么书
It's normal not to appreciate it
鉴赏不来也是正常
Why should you criticize her
您又何必苛责她
Let me accompany you to enjoy the paintings
还是臣妾来陪您赏画吧
This is the authentic work of the Tang family
这唐大家的真迹
It's really extraordinary
果然不同凡响
Look at the distant mountains
您看这远山
Ordinary people draw distant mountains
普通人画远山
Often with light ink
往往用淡墨
And he did the opposite
而他却反其道而行之
Put the distant mountains
把远处的山峦
Expressed with heavy painting and heavy colors
用浓抹重彩表现了出来
It can be said that viewing heaven and earth with the heart
可谓是以心观天地
And heaven and earth are all in my heart
而天地尽在心中
Good good
好 不错
As expected of being my beloved concubine
不愧是朕的爱妃
Well said
说得真好
Okay, you guys go ahead
行了 你们继续
The emperor drives
皇上起驾
Slave retires
奴才告退
Sister I'm sorry
姐姐 对不起
You were kind enough to let me come
你一番好意让我前来
And I destroyed
我却破坏了
Your pleasure with the emperor
您和皇上的雅兴
And you know
你也知道
I'm really interested in painting
我对绘画实在
What does that sister think I mean by this move
那妹妹觉得我此举何意
It won't be
不会的
Sister, you can't do this to me
姐姐你不可能这样对我
Now that you've guessed
你既然已经猜到了
Why should you be so naive
为什么还要如此天真
What a good trick
真是好手段啊
How many times did you save me
你几番搭救我
Deliberately approaching me
刻意接近我
Just for
就是为了
Understand my weakness, right
了解我的弱点是吗
You know I'm from an ordinary background
你深知我出身平凡
Don't understand painting
不懂绘画
Not to mention appreciation
更别提鉴赏了
Today you asked me to come over
今天你让我过来
Just to make the emperor
就是为了让皇上
Loathing at me
对我心生厌恶
My sister really does
妹妹果真有
An exquisite heart with seven orifices
一颗七窍玲珑的心啊
Why
为什么
The world is bustling for profit
天下熙熙 皆为利来
You remember
你记住了
There's everything in this palace
这皇宫里什么都有
It's just impossible to have
就是不可能有
True sisterhood
真正的姐妹情谊
I will keep in mind
我定会谨记
What the imperial concubine said
贵妃娘娘说的话
Let's go back and reflect on it
这就回去好好反思
Mr. Wei
魏总
Why do you propose
您为什么提议
Let her take over
让她去接替呢
With her current qualifications
就她现在的资历
It's simply impossible
根本就不可能
Responsible for overseas operations
负责海外业务
I started by thinking
我一开始就想
Let her be Li Su's assistant
让她做李溯的助理
With Li Su's character
以李溯的性格
He simply couldn't
他根本就不会
Like the last one
喜欢上一个
Someone who is not good enough
不够优秀的人
And he treats his work
而他对待工作
And very harsh
又十分地严苛
Assistant is not easy to be
助理并不好做
He Jiaojiao has no experience
何皎皎没有经验
Plus my help
再加上我的推波助澜
It is inevitable that she will make mistakes
她犯错是必然
And once she makes a mistake
而她一旦犯错
Li Su will beat it from the bottom of his heart
李溯就会打从心底里
Really loathe her
真正地厌恶她
This is called killing people and killing their hearts
这才叫杀人诛心
What if she really refuses
那她万一真的拒绝
As an assistant
做助理呢
Do you think Li Su
你觉得李溯
It's possible to like it
有可能会喜欢
A Lian Challenge
一个连挑战
A woman who doesn't dare to accept it
都不敢接受的女人吗
Mr. Wei, you are so amazing
魏总 您真是太厉害了
Casually
随随便便
That set her up a dead end
就给她设了一个死局
Dasu, you just got off work
大溯 你也才下班哪
Why do you suddenly call me that
你怎么突然这么叫我
When I was a kid
我小时候
That's what I call you
不就这么叫你的
Just be casual after get off work
下班了就随意点嘛
Okay
行
How about sending me home
怎么样 送我回家吧
Come on, I'm just back home
拜托 我可是刚回国
You wouldn't let myself
你不会让我自己
Drive back
开车回去吧
Okay, I'll send you
行 我送你
-Yeah -Yeah
-好 -走吧
Go home
回家
Finally know
终于知道
Why Wei Yahan
为什么魏雅涵
You're gonna praise me and kill me
要捧杀我了
I didn't expect it to be the 21st century
没想到都二十一世纪了
She's still robbing men from me
她还在跟我抢男人
It's really boring
真是无聊
Good morning, Mr. Li
李总 早上好啊
Let me press it for you
我帮您按
You don't have to worry about the assistant
助理的事情你不用担心
If you don't want to, you can
要是不愿意的话 可以
Mr. Li, I'm ready
李总 我已经准备好了
Today it's me as an assistant
今天是我作为助理
First day in office
上任的第一天
Please take care of me
还请您多多关照
I thought you were scared
我还以为你怕了
What are you afraid of
怕什么
Can you still eat me
难道你还能吃了我不成
Mr. Li
李总
I didn't mean that
我不是那个意思啊
Don't think too much about it
你别多想
Think more
多想
What do you mean thinking
你是指 想什么
Mr. Li, the elevator door is closing soon
李总 电梯门快关了
Please fast forward
您快进吧
Bye
拜拜
Bye-bye, Mr. Li
李总 拜拜
You
你
What are you doing
你要干吗
Have you figured it out
你想好了
Work is not just fun
工作可不是玩玩而已
I've never had
我从来都没有
Just thought about having fun
想过玩玩而已
So
所以
That night
那个晚上
Are you serious
你是认真的
I
我
Go to work first
先去工作
Come and report for duty in ten minutes
十分钟后过来报到
Bye
拜拜
Today is a good day
今天是个好日子
Everything can be done tomorrow
明天的事都能成
Xu Tezhu
许特助
Xiao He
小何呀
Come, come, come, this way, this way
来来来 这边 这边
Come on, come on, come on, come on
来 过来 过来 过来
Then you later
那个 你以后啊
Don't call me Special Assistant Xu anymore
不要再叫我许特助了
From now on, you will be Special Assistant He
以后你才是何特助
Good
好
I've packed up all this stuff
这个东西我都收拾好了
And over there
那边呢
Is an assistant job guide
是助理工作指南
Anyway, it's very simple
总之呢 特别简单
Just four words
就四个字
Responsive
有求必应
Come on, Xiao He
小何 加油
Refuel
加油
Today is a good day
今天是个好日子
So happy
这么开心
Give me a cup of coffee
给我一杯咖啡
Okay, Mr. Li
好的 李总
Mr. Li, your coffee
李总 您的咖啡
Already warm
已经是温的
You're ready to drink
您可以喝了
Why is the coffee a little sweet today
怎么今天咖啡有点甜呀
I'm following Special Assistant Xu
我是按照许特助
The little notebook I gave
给的那个小本本
It says above
上面写的
One-third package of sugar
三分之一包糖
It shouldn't be wrong
应该没有错
Why don't I make another cup
要不我再泡一杯
It's okay
没事
You can go back first
你先回去吧
OK
好的
Maybe you're sweet
可能是你比较甜
Mr. Li, your snacks
李总 您的点心
But you're not
可是您不是
Do you always skip snacks in the morning
早上一向不吃点心吗
Forget
忘了
OK
好的
If you still need it
如果您还需要的话
Keep calling me
继续叫我
Mr. Li, your newspaper
李总 您的报纸
But now
可是现在
It's more convenient to watch the news on your mobile phone
用手机看新闻比较方便
I like newspapers
我喜欢报纸
E-newsletters are more environmentally
电子报比较环保
Mr. Li
李总
The work arrangement has been given to you
工作安排已经给您
It was sent to the mailbox
发到邮箱了
Do you need anything else
您还有别的需要吗
You read it to me again
你再给我读一遍
Mr. Li, I'm an assistant
李总 我是助理
Not a voice assistant
不是语音助手
Hello, Special Assistant Xu
喂 许特助
I would like to ask
我想请问一下
Mr. Li has been in demand
李总一直需求
So many
这么多的吗
No.
没有啊
As long as it's arranged
只要安排好了
Basically nothing happened
基本没什么事情
Then why did he
那为什么他
Xiao He Ya
小何呀
If you feel the pressure
你要是感觉到压力
You can look at the drawer on the right hand side
可以看看右手边的抽屉
I left you a magic weapon
我给你留了法宝
Xiao He
小何
You must stick to it
你一定要坚持下去啊
Don't let Mr. Li again
别再让李总
Calls me back again
又把我叫回来了
OK
好的
Hello
喂
Come to my office
来一下我办公室
OK
好的
Mr. Li
李总
Is there anything else you can do
您还有什么事情吗
Things on my side
我这边事情
There are really a lot
实在也是非常多
If you don't have
如果您没有
If anything happens
什么事情的话
Would you please call me less
请您少叫我 可以吗
Just my first day as my assistant
才做我助理第一天
You can't stand it
你就受不了了
That's what you're talking about
这就是你说的
Get ready
做好准备了
At your disposal
随时听您吩咐
My tie is messed up
我领带乱了
Help me sort it out
帮我整理一下
How
怎么
Come on
来啊
Mr. Li, I can't wear a tie
李总 我不会系领带
You wouldn't
你是不会呢
Still unwilling
还是不愿意啊
Mr. Li
李总
I really can't wear a tie
我真的不会系领带
Try it
试试嘛
Can't let the boss
总不能让老板
Do such a small thing
干这种小事吧
Mr. Li
李总
I'm really not very good at it
我真的不太会呀
It's okay
没事
I can allow you to be stupid once in a while
我可以偶尔允许你很笨
Mr. Li
李总
Working hours
上班时间
Can you stop making such jokes
可以不要开这种玩笑吗
So what do you mean is
那你的意思是
Can I talk when I get off work
我下班了就可以说吗
Will Mr. Li go to the meeting together
李总 一起去开会吗
Let me do it
还是我来吧
It's okay, that's it
没事 就这样吧
Let's go
走吧
Mr. Li
李总
Are you satisfied with the new assistant
新的助理您还满意吗
She really doesn't have much experience
她确实没有太多经验
If it doesn't fit
如果不合适的话
It's fine. Just her for now
挺好的 暂时就她吧
Attach a tie
连系领带
I don't know anything like this
这样的事情都不太会
There will still be a lot of room for development
还会有很多发展空间啊
Now it seems
现在看来
Some people are full of mistakes and omissions
有人就是错漏百出
Why do you suddenly say this
你怎么突然说这个啊
Sometimes
有的时候
We should probably
我们或许应该
Be more patient
更有耐心一些
Because some people are worth waiting for
因为有的人值得等待
Understand
明白